Film and Media Studies Program Records UA082
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Film and Media Studies Program Records
1989 -- 2005
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Communications and Media Studies Program
Film and Media Studies Program
UA082
0.25 Linear Feet 1 box
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Communications and Media Studies Program, annual reports; Invitations; and Audiovisual materials.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains annual reports, invitations, and audiovisual materials from the Film and Media Studies Program.
Biographical / Historical
In 1982, the Communications Cluster was founded within the Experimental College at Tufts University. The cluster was developed in response to student demand and the perceived need to develop an "academic emphasis on communications and media." It was dubbed the Communications and Media Studies (CMS) program in 1985 and won approval as an interdisciplinary minor in 1996. In 2015, the CMS program was expanded and renamed to become the Film and Media Studies program.
The Film and Media Studies (FMS) program at Tufts University is an interdisciplinary program designed to educate Tufts students about the art and social impact of film, television, and other modern media within a liberal arts curriculum. FMS emphasizes the importance of media literacy in an era in which knowledge about people and events comes primarily from mass and social media sources. The program can be undertaken as a major or a minor, with all students required to complete Art of the Moving Image as part of their studies. The program also offers options to engage in a Senior Honors Thesis and a Film and Media Production Sequence.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Centers and Institutes; Curriculum and Instruction -- Teaching Material
- Communications and Media Studies Program, annual reports, 1989 -- 1996; UA082.001; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains annual reports generated by the Communications and Media Studies Program.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Annual report, 1989 -- 1990; UA082.001.001.00001 (Box UA082 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1992 -- 1993; UA082.001.001.00002 (Box UA082 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1993 -- 1994; UA082.001.001.00003 (Box UA082 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1994 -- 1995; UA082.001.001.00004 (Box UA082 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1995 -- 1996; UA082.001.001.00005 (Box UA082 Shared 1)
- Invitations, 1993 -- 1995; UA082.002; 0.1 Linear Feet 1 folder
  This series is open for research.
  This series contains invitations to Communications and Media events.
  - Invitations, 1993 -- 1995; UA082.002.001.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box UA082 Shared 1)
- Audiovisual materials, 2004 -- 2005; UA082.003; 0.1 Linear Feet 1 folder
  This series consists of two copies of "Producing Films for Social Change."
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred on 2013-08-07 from accession 2013.144.
  - Producing Films for Social Change, 2004 -- 2005; UA082.003.001.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box UA082 Shared 1)
- COVID-eo film festival student films, 2020; UA082.000012; 2.32 Gigabytes; 12 Digital Object(s)
  Transferred by Tufts Film and Media Studies department, accession UA-2021-054, 2021.
  This series is arranged in alphabetical order by student's last name.
  This series contains student films created for the COVID-eo Film Festival.
  - Hesh's of the Afternoon, by Eli Beutel, 2020; UA082.000013; 202.14 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
  - Dead Time, by James Boots-Ebenfield, 2020; UA082.000014; 147.62 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
  - The Good Stuff, by Aidan Chang, 2020; UA082.000015; 35.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
  - Dorm Work, by Tyler Markovich, 2020; UA082.000016; 35.62 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
  - Front, by Tyler Markovich, 2020; UA082.000017; 144.95 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
  - Looking at Moss, by Donovan Menard, 2020; UA082.000018; 283.15 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
  - A Rube Goldberg Machine, by Bach Ngo, 2020; UA082.000019; 75.29 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
  - Miss You Too, by Rosa Stern Pait, 2020; UA082.000020; 306.09 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
  - March 268th, by Maya Pockrose, 2020; UA082.000021; 430.71 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
  - Mask Fishing, by Alexandra Soo, 2020; UA082.000022; 709.53 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
  - Wear a Mask, by Olivia White, 2020; UA082.000023; 9.22 Megabytes; 1 Minutes